## **Pedro Vieira**

UX Designer / Graphic Designer

www.pedrovieira.design hey@pedrovieira.design

### **About**

UX designer, passionate about creativity and sustainability, with a background in graphic design.

Resourceful and creative problem solver, experienced in design thinking processes.

Helped teams run through design cycles to explore, create and deliver user-focused, value-driven concepts for brands and products.

### Skills

User-Centered Design

Design Thinking

Competitive Analysis

User Research

**User Personas** 

Information Architecture

User Flows

Iterative Wireframing and Prototyping Usability and Preference Testing

Language Systems and Styleguides

HTML and CSS Fundamentals

### Skills

Figma Miro
Illustrator Figjam
Photoshop After Effects

## Education

#### CareerFoundry

User Experience Design, UX Certification Intensive project-based mentored training program Mar 2022

#### **IADE - Creative University**

Postgraduate, Design Thinking & Prototyping Jul 2017

### **Polytechnic Institute of Castelo Branco**

Bachelor's Degree, Visual Communication Design

# Languages

Portuguese (Native)
English (Professional proficiency)

# **UX Projects**

### Viv - Health & Wellbeing app

UX/UI Designer - CareerFoundry Project

linkedin.com/in/pedro-vieira-design

Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- Created an inclusive, responsive health web portal designed to help people manage daily health issues.
- Conducted user research, crafted wireframes and prototypes, analyzed usability tests results and implemented users' feedback.
- Refined designs according to accessibility principles and prepared them for dev handoff.

View project > pedrovieira.design/viv.html

### Speakin' - Language Learning app

UX Designer - CareerFoundry Project

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021

 Conceptualised a language learning mobile app by taking the project through design thinking stages, including competitive analysis, user research, information architecture, ideation, prototyping and user testing.

View project > pedrovieira.design/speakin.html

# **Professional Experience**

### Freelance Graphic Designer

Freelancer, Portugal

Since Sep 2009

 Worked for a diverse range of self-sourced clients, translating briefings into meaningful concepts and unique brand assets, resulting in strong visual identities in line with clients' culture and business objectives.

At Mendes Gonçalves S.A. / Santarém, Portugal

#### Creative Designer - Innovation Lab.

2017 - 2021

- Co-led a qualitative data-gathering project by designing an online store with food-product co-creation features, allowing for a direct connection with the target audience and a better understanding of consumers' needs.
- Re-designed the product innovation process, introducing user centered methods, ideation workshops and product prototyping, resulting in a fluid, iterative process and enabeling market-relevant outputs.

#### **Graphic Designer - Brand Keeper**

2012 - 2017

- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team to revitalize the company's main brand, generating disruptive concepts that lead to a multi-awarded brand and increased top-of-mind awareness.
- Coordinated the brand application to online and offline assets, including website, online store and 200+ packaging items, ensuring visual guidelines adherence and delivering a consistent brand experience.

### **Graphic Designer - Junior**

2009 - 2012

Implemented visual identities across all print and digital marketing materials
by continually collaborating with partners, suppliers, and departments,
guaranteeing visual communication cohesion and boosting brand visibility.